Even kindergartners deserve a little respect.
Recess: All Growed Down is a family, comedy,
animation film directed by Howy Parkins.
and The Recess Gang are kidnapped by the Third Street School's
kindergartners, who are in turn being bullied by a new kid in their class.
T.J. Detweiler (voice), played by Myles Jeffrey.
Spinelli (voice), played by Pamela Adlon.
Principal Prickley (voice), played by Dabney Coleman.
Gretchen Grundler (voice), played by Ashley Johnson.
Miss Grotke (voice), played by Allyce Beasley.
Vince LaSalle (voice), played by Rickey D'Shon Collins.
Recess is an American animated television series created by Paul Germain and Joe Ansolabehere (credited on marketing materials and late-series title cards as "Paul &
Joe") and produced by Walt Disney Television Animation, with animation done by Grimsaem, Anivision, Plus One Animation, Sunwoo Animation, and Toon City.
The series focuses on six elementary school students and their
interaction with other classmates and teachers.
The title refers to the recess period during the daily schedule, in the North American tradition of
educational schooling, when students are not in lessons and are outside in the schoolyard.
During recess, the children form their own society, complete with government and
a class structure, set against the backdrop of a regular school.
Recess premiered on September 13, 1997, on ABC, as part of Disney's
One Saturday Morning block (later known as ABC Kids).
The series ended on November 5, 2001, with 65
half-hour episodes and four seasons in total.
The success and lasting appeal of the series saw it being syndicated to numerous channels, including
ABC's sister channels Disney Channel and Toon Disney (which later became Disney XD).
In 2001, Walt Disney Pictures released a theatrical film
based on the series, Recess: School's Out.
It was followed by a direct-to-video second film entitled Recess
Christmas: Miracle on Third Street that same year.
In 2003, two more direct-to-video films were released: Recess: All
Growed Down and Recess: Taking the Fifth Grade.
The characters made their final appearance in a crossover episode for Lilo &
Stitch: The Series until Vince returned in an episode of Chibiverse.
The tone is lighthearted.